

#### JUNIOR AT RENSSELAER POLYTECHNIC INSTITUT

Greater Boston Area, MA

☑ nguyenjason06@gmail.com | 🎢 dangitjason.github.io | 🖸 DangItJason | 🛅 jnguyen576

# Summary.

Technical leader who loves empowering a team to turn ideas into a reality and uses coding as a tool to solve challenging problems. Ready to utilize learned technical skills, academic background and leadership experience to contribute to a greater cause.

## Skills

Languages: Python, C/C++, Java, Javascript (+ES6), HTML/CSS

Technologies: Linux, React.js, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB (Mongoose), Bootstrap, Git, npm

# **Education**

### **Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute**

Trov, NY

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE, 3.5 GPA

Expected Graduation: May 2022

- Dean's Honor List: Fall 18', Spring 19'
- Coursework: Data Structures, Discrete Math, Differential Equations, Multivariable Calculus, Intro to Algorithms, Principles of Software, Operating Systems, Computer Communication Networks, Computer Organization

# **Experience**

#### **Rensselaer Center for Open Source**

Trov. NY

DEVELOPER AND PROJECT LEAD

May 2020 - Aug. 2020

- Led a team of 5 developers to create a platform that connects campus students to tutors and provides tutors a business management tool.
- · Wrote a software requirement specification to identify project scope, requirements, goals and high level design.
- Used React.js framework and Bootstrap to develop clean, functional user dashboards.
- · Created RESTful API endpoints using Node.js and Express.js frameworks to communicate with a NoSQL database.
- Follows Model-View-Controller design pattern for simultaneous development, cohesion and performance.
- · Used Agile methods to collaborate, organize development efforts and deliver expected acceptance criteria.

## **Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute Science Department**

Troy, NY

Undergraduate Computer Science Teaching Assistant

Aug. 2019 - Dec. 2019

- Guided new computer science students to build and develop proper programming practices during lab periods.
- · Directly influenced growth of 30+ students through instructing with Python programming exercises.

# **Projects**

You can view each project at dangitjason.github.io

## **Multi-threaded Chat Server**

C, LINUX, SOCKET PROGRAMMING

Aug. 2020

Developed a multi-threaded chat server in C that allows communication between connected clients over TCP and UDP connections.

#### A\* Path Finding Algorithm Visualization

PYTHON, TKINTER May 2020

- Developed a python script that uses A\* search algorithm to find the lowest cost path from start to end destinations.
- Uses Tkinter Python module to visualize the algorithm's decisions and add obstacles to grid.

#### **Login and SignUp System**

JS ES6, BOOTSTRAP CSS, NODE.JS, EXPRESS.JS, REACT.JS, MONGODB, NPM

Apr. 2020 - May 2020

- Developed a functional login and sign-up page for a full-stack fitness application.
- Uses React.js framework and Bootstrap CSS for front-end UI.
- Created RESTful API endpoints using Node.js and Express.js to support CRUD operations.

#### **GroupMe Chat Bot**

Python, Google Calender API Dec. 2019

- Developed a chat bot using Python to inform and remind group members of weekly upcoming events.
- Retrieved, stored and pushed important dates through Google Calendar API.